[
    {
        "question": "A couple enters a grand ballroom only to find the occupants are dead. There has been no crime committed. The couple is not concerned by what they have found. How is this possible?",
        "answer": "The couple is scuba diving on a sunken cruise ship. The occupants in the ballroom had drowned when the ship sank suddenly in a terrible disaster at sea."
    },
    {
        "question": "A carrot, a scarf, and five pieces of coal are found lying on your neighbor’s lawn. Nobody put them on the lawn, but there is a simple, logical reason why they are there. What is it?",
        "answer": "The items were used by children to build a snowman that has now melted."
    },
    {
       "question": "An elderly woman lives on the 35th floor and hates taking the stairs. Every day she takes the elevator down to the lobby floor to go to work. When she comes home from work, she takes the elevator to the 25th floor and walks the rest of the way up, except on days when it rains. Those days she takes the elevator all the way home. Why does she walk the last ten flights of stairs if she hates it so much?",
       "answer": "The elderly woman is too petite to reach the button for the 35th floor. She can only reach the 25th-floor button. On days when it rains, she uses her umbrella to hit the button for the 35th floor."
    },
    {
        "question": "You are driving a school bus. The bus is empty when you begin your route. At the first stop, 4 people get on. At the second stop, 8 people get on and 2 get off. At the third stop, 3 people get off and 4 get on. What color are the bus driver’s eyes?",
        "answer": "The color of your eyes."
    },
    {
        "question": "A baby falls out of a window of a 20 story building, yet survives. How?",
        "answer": "The window was on the ground floor."
    },
    {
        "question": "Rachael and Monica have moved into a shared house with several other occupants. Monica doesn’t like their new accommodation though because of the angry and aggressive cat that greeted them when they first walked in. Rachael realizes that there isn’t really a problem. Why?",
        "answer": "There is a mirror near the entrance. Monica is a cat, saw her reflection, and thought that it was another cat challenging her for territory. Rachael can cover up the mirror until Monica becomes settled, but Monica will figure it out eventually even if Rachael does nothing."
    },
    {
        "question": "A family has a chicken coop for their one dozen hens. Late one night, a terrible storm came through their area and killed all but eight chickens. How many chickens did the family have the next morning?",
        "answer": "The family still had 12 hens, four dead, and eight alive."
    },
    {
        "question": "A woman with her barking dog enters a room and presses a button. Within seconds, she instantly loses 20 pounds and the dog stops barking. How did she lose the weight?",
        "answer": "The room is actually an elevator. When she gets inside to go down to her room, the elevator accelerates downward, making her weight temporarily lower."
    },
    {
        "question": "The sound of Brian’s snoring is usually just annoying, but today it causes terror and panic. Why?",
        "answer": "Brian is a bus driver."
    },
    {
        "question": "A woman who is in a department store fills her basket to the top and leaves the store without paying. Although she is seen, no one calls the police or attempts to stop her. Why?",
        "answer": "The woman works there.  She is filling the basket with trash and taking it out to the dumpster."
    },
    {
        "question": "A man is sentenced to death. He has to choose from three rooms to receive his punishment. The first room has a firing squad with guns loaded. The second room has a blazing fire. The third room is full of tigers that haven’t eaten for six months. Which room should he choose?",
        "answer": "The room of tigers. If the tigers haven’t eaten in six months, they’re dead."
    },
    {
        "question": "A man opened a door, screamed, and then was found dead a few minutes later. No gunshots were heard in the area. What happened to him?",
        "answer": "He was on an airplane and opened the door while the plane was in flight, falling to his death."
    },
    {
        "question": "While walking across a large open field, you come across a woman that has died very suddenly, unexpectedly, and only a very short time ago. You look around but there is no one and nothing except for an unopened package next to the woman. How did she die?",
        "answer": "The unopened package was the woman’s parachute."
    },
    {
        "question": "Jason’s dad couldn’t keep his son from playing video games. To keep Jason from playing video games all the time, the dad grabbed a hammer and solved the problem. Now he can play video games but Jason cannot. What did the dad do?",
        "answer": "The dad built a shelf out of Jason’s reach and put the video game console up there. The dad can still reach it to play but Jason cannot."
    },
    {
        "question": "A man and his wife raced through the streets. They stopped and the husband got out of the car. When he returned, his wife was dead and there was a stranger in the car. What happened?",
        "answer": "The wife was about to have a baby. The husband drove them to the hospital. The husband left to get a wheelchair but the baby was born in the meantime. The wife died in childbirth."
    },
    {
        "question": "A woman enters a large metal tube. She is overcome with fear and clenches her boyfriend’s hand tightly. She is visibly shaken. Her boyfriend gently rubs her arms and speaks softly to her, but is unaffected himself. A few hours later, the woman’s boyfriend tells her that it’s time to go and her torment ends. What was happening to the woman?",
        "answer": "The woman is terrified of flying but must travel to see a dying relative and this adds to her stress level. Her boyfriend does his best to comfort her during the few hours of the flight."
    },
    {
        "question": "After a night of partying with her friends, a sorority girl arrives home and finds that she cannot enter her house. She’s sure that she’s at the right home, but she cannot get inside. What happened that makes entering her home impossible?",
        "answer": "Her friends took her keys away from her the night before because she had too much to drink. They ordered her an Uber to get home and kept her keys, which meant she didn’t have her house key."
    },
    {
        "question": "The man finds himself commuting to work in his car every day. Upon arrival to work each morning, he proceeds to drive his car in a circle four times before finally parking it and entering his office building. Why does the man drive in circles every day?",
        "answer": "The man works in a crowded part of downtown and is required to park on the fifth floor of a parking structure every day."
    },
    {
        "question": " If you were alone in a dark room, with only one match and an oil lamp, a fireplace, and a candle to choose from, which would you light first?",
        "answer": "The match."
    },
    {
        "question": "There are a dozen eggs in a carton. Twelve people each take a single egg, but there is one egg left in the carton. How?",
        "answer": "The 12th person takes the egg and the carton, leaving the egg inside."
    },
    {
        "question": "A woman had two sons. They were born at the same hour on the same day of the same month in the same year. However, they were not twins. How could this be?",
        "answer": "Her two sons were part of a set of triplets (or quadruplets!)."
    }
]
